Guide to the Fred Chappell Papers, 1944-2019 and undated RL.00213
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings by Chappell Series, 1960-1997 and undated
  - Fiction Subseries, 1963-1996 and undated
    - Individual stories, in alphabetical order:
      - Thatch Strikes Back, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WF-4)
      - The Three Boxes, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WF-4)
      - The Twins: Story of Anselm the Wrestler, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WF-4)
      - The Watch, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WF-4)
      - Weird Tales, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WF-4)
      - Witchcraft, undated, rec'd 1991 July (Box WF-4)
      - The World of Nature as By Harlequin Conceived, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WF-4)
      - Untitled story, manuscript, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WF-4)
      - Untitled story, typescript, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WF-4)
      - Untitled story, manuscript, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WF-4)
  - Poetry Subseries, ca. 1960-1996 and undated
    Arranged alphabetically by title, books first followed by individual poems. Versions of collected poems may appear under their own title or that of the collection. Additional versions may appear in the Notebooks Subseries.
    - Bloodfire (1978), 3 folders (Box WP-1)
      - miscellaneous manuscripts, undated (Box WP-1)
      - dead manuscript, 1978 (Box WP-1)
      - proof, 1978 (Box WP-1)
    - C (1993), 2 folders
      - typescript photocopy, undated, rec'd 1993 July (Box WP-1)
      - typescript photocopy, undated (Box WP-1)
    - Castle Tzingal (1984), 5 folders
      - notebooks and partial typescript, undated (Box WP-1)
      - typescript fragment, undated, rec'd 1997 July (Box WP-1)
      - typescript, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-1)
      - typescript photocopy, undated (Box WP-1)
      - proof, 1984 (Box WP-1)
    - Earthsleep (1980) See also Oversize Material, 1 folder
      - edited typescript, 1980 (Box WP-1)
    - Family Gathering (1996), 4 folders
      - partial typescript, undated (Box WP-1)
      - partial typescript, 1/12/96 (Box WP-1)
      - typescript, undated, rec'd 1997 July (Box WP-1)
      - proof, 6/19/96 (Box WP-1)
    - First and Last Words (1989), 6 folders
      - miscellaneous typescripts and manuscripts, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-1)
      - corrected typescript photocopy, undated, rec'd 1991 July (Box WP-1)
      - partial typescript, "xerox of final version," undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-1)
      - typescript photocopy, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-1)
      - dead manuscript, 1989 May 29 (Box WP-1)
      - proofs, ca. 1989 (Box WP-1)
    - Hour of My Lives (unpublished), 1 folder
      - typescript, undated (Box WP-1)
    - Look Back All the Green Valley (unpublished) See also Spring Garden, 2 folders
      - typescript, undated (Box WP-1)
      - partial typescript, undated, rec'd 1995 June (Box WP-1)
    - River (1975), 2 folders
      - manuscripts, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-1)
      - typescript, 1973 Oct. 1 (Box WP-1)
    - Source (1985), 4 folders
      - notebook, undated, and miscellaneous typescripts, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-1)
      - typescript, undated (Box WP-1)
      - dead manuscript, ca. 1985 (Box WP-1)
      - proof, 1985 (Box WP-1)
    - Spring Garden (1995) See also Look Back All the Green Valley, 2 folders
      - partial typescript, undated, rec'd 1995 June (Box WP-1)
      - partial typescript, undated, rec'd 1995 June (Box WP-1)
    - Wind Mountain (1979) See also Oversize Material, 1 folder (Box WP-2)
      - dead manuscript, ca. 1979 (Box WP-2)
    - The World Between the Eyes (1971) See also Oversize Material, 2 folders
      - author-corrected typescript, undated (Box WP-2)
      - dead manuscript, ca. 1971 (Box WP-2)
    - Untitled Collection, 1 folder
      - typescript, undated (Box WP-2)
    - Individual poems, in alphabetical order:
      - 2 for Michael, undated (Box WP-2)
      - According to the best of my information, undated, rec'd 1970 Jan. (Box WP-2)
      - Adoration of Sunlight, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - After Revelation, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Afternoons with Allen, undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-2)
      - Afterseasons, countershades, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Al's Billiards Bar [?], ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - An American Suicide Speaks to the Asian Dead, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Animal Dream, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - An Anniversary Toast, undated, rec'd July, 1995 (Box WP-2)
      - Ants at the Sugar Jar, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Apollo the God of Summer, ca. 1964 June (Box WP-2)
      - Appalachian Apples, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - At Ross's Landing: Anniversary Poem, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - At the Grave of Virgil Campbell, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Attis and Adonis, undated, rec'd 1970 Jan. (Box WP-2)
      - Aunt Alicia, undated, rec'd 1995 July (Box WP-2)
      - The Autumn of the Indifferent Trombone, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Awakening to Music, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Ballads of Good Advice, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Bear, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Beech Tap Remembrance, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Beer Drinking in America, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Being and Becoming, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - The Betrayal, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-2)
      - Birthday 35: Diary Entry, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Blessing, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-2)
      - Blues for Bird, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Body of Knowledge, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Bon Voyage, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Boys with the Restless Eyes, undated, rec'd 1970 Apr. and 1985 Oct., 2 items (Box WP-2)
      - Brooks Robinson, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Burning the Frankenstein Monster: Elegiac Letter to Richard Dillard, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Busted Flush, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Cabin in Hill Shadow, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Caesura, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Caligari by Dreamlight, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Canticles and Compliments of Common Creatures, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Capacity for Pain, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Cello, Solo, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Changeling, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Christopher Smart, in His Madness (2 versions), ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Class of '54, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Cleaning the Well, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Cobb, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Coming To, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Common and the Uncommon, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-2)
      - Confession Fragment, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Contra Martial, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-2)
      - Cousin Lilias, undated Cousin Lilias, undated (Box WP-2)
      - Cow, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Cupid Asleep, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - D.W. Griffith: Way Down East, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Dead Soldiers, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Death of W.H. Auden, ca. 1963 (Box WP-2)
      - Delayed by Mongol/Bendit Forces at the National Airport, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Detroit Pontiac, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Disencampment of the Future, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Dispatches. See Messages (Box WP-2)
      - Dr. Fell, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Dr. Zorlo's (?) Mirror of Miracle Shadows, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-2)
      - Dreigroschen oper, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Dressage, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Early Concert, undated, rec'd Apr. 1970 (Box WP-2)
      - Earth Emergent Drifts the Fire River, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Elkin Robert (Under Ember), undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Embitterment and The Embitterment of Charity, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-2)
      - EMF [Eastern Music Festival] Poems, ca. 1986 July (Box WP-2)
      - Enfolded: For Amy Charles, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-2)
      - Epigram, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Epitaph, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-2)
      - Epithalamion, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Establish, charge, and Silver, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Establish, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Estrangement, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Eternity, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Exile, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Extra Innings, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Familiar Poem, ca. 1960 (Box WP-2)
      - The Far Carnival, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Farm, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Fast Ball, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Feast: An Afterword to Annie Dillard's Pilgrim at Tinker Creek, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-2)
      - February, 1969 June 29 (Box WP-2)
      - Festival, 1986 July 14 (Box WP-2)
      - The Fevered Child, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Firewater, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Firewood, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Fix, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Flowering Croesus, undated, rec'd 1970 Apr. (Box WP-2)
      - For Reynolds Price, undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-2)
      - For Reynolds Price: Horace 1.1, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-2)
      - A Friend, Drowned Fishing for Trout, ca. 1961 (Box WP-2)
      - Georgics Prolog and Allegory: Vermeer's 'The Astronomer,' undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-2)
      - The Gift and The Valley, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Gift to be Simple: A Prologue to Aaron Copland's Appalachian Spring, undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-2)
      - A Glorious Twilight, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-2)
      - Heath, Age 8: His New Drum, ca. 1995, and Heath, Age 2: Trying to Talk, ca. 1995 (Box WP-2)
      - History is a Force in Personal Life, Even, undated, rec'd 1970 Jan. (Box WP-2)
      - The House of the Fathers, undated, rec'd 1992 June (Box WP-2)
      - Hymn and Hir, ca. 1964 June (Box WP-2)
      - I am François (Three After Villon), undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Iago by Verdi, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Ice Coquette, undated, rec'd 1970 Apr. and 1985 Oct. (2 items) (Box WP-2)
      - Ideally Grasping the Actual Flower, (2 versions) undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-2)
      - An Impersonation: Epilogue to The Memoirs of Sherlock Holmes An Impersonation: Epilogue to The Memoirs of Sherlock Holmes (Box WP-2)
      - In Another Country, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Influences and Dreigroschen Oper, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Influences, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Intermezzo of Fireflies, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Intimation, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Invasion News, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Invitation au Voyage, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Irrational Kite-Flying Letter to George Garrett, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Islet, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Jim Applewhite Dreams in Springtime, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Junk Ball, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Kisses, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Ladybug, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Last Rose of Summer, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Latencies, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - The Latter Years: An Epilogue to The Wind in the Willows, (2 versions) undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-2)
      - Legions, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Let Me Lie, Will You? ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Literature, (2 versions) undated, rec'd 1987 July and 1989 June (Box WP-2)
      - The Long Passing Away of the Visible: for Jim Wayne Miller, ca. Sept., 1996 (Box WP-2)
      - Lovecraft, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Malgré Lui and The Epigrammatist, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-2)
      - The Man Twice Married to Fire, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Marine (Three After Rimbaud), undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Martial, Lib. IX, 4, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Mays, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - McCrary's Boots, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Mean What You Say, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Messages, (4 versions) undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-2)
      - Mirror of Looking, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Mockingbird, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - A Momentary Gallantry, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-2)
      - Monmoor, an Island, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Monologue of the Candle Traveling Cancrizans in Time, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Morning Snow and Visit to My Brother, undated, rec'd 1970 Jan. (Box WP-2)
      - Music as a Woman Imperfectly Perceived, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Cough, undated, rec'd 1970 Apr. and 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Father Joins the Klan, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Father Washes His Hands, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Grandfather Gets Doused, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Grandmother Washes Her Feet, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Literary Reputation: A Poem, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Mother Shoots the Breeze, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Mother's Hard Row to Hoe, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Son: His New Drum, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - My Son, Aged Two Years, 1963 Dec. 7 (2 items) (Box WP-2)
      - The Naked Ark, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Narcissus and Echo, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Nightcap, undated, rec'd 1991 July (Box WP-2)
      - Northwest Airlines, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - Novel, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-2)
      - O Sacred Head Now Wounded, undated, rec'd 1986 June and 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Ode to Melancholy, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-3)
      - The Old Actor, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Old Mountain Woman Reading Her Bible, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - One-Way Mirror, undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-3)
      - The Ordinary: a prologue to Tolstoy's 'Death of Ivan Ilych,' undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-3)
      - Overcoming the Conquered, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Pan's Song, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Paradiso XXX, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Peaceable Kingdom of Emerald Windows, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Performance, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Perspective and Kisses, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Phantom Pattern: A Pantoum, 1996. (Box WP-3)
      - The Phantom Pontoon: A Pantoum [?], undated The Phantom Pontoon: A Pantoum [?], undated (Box WP-3)
      - Pierrot Escapes, undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-3)
      - Pindar, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-3)
      - Poem After Hunting, undated, rec'd 1970 Jan. (Box WP-3)
      - The Poems of William Meredith, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Poets are Rattling like Rusty, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - A Prayer for the Mountains, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - A Prayer for Truthfulness, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Prayer to All Herbs, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Presence, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (2 items) (Box WP-3)
      - A Prologue to the Georgics, undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-3)
      - Purple Hat, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Rain on Hemphill Valley, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Reader, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-3)
      - Readings, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Regret, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Renting, ca. June, 1964 (Box WP-3)
      - Rib, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Rider, undated, rec'd July, 1990 (Box WP-3)
      - The River, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The River Awakening in the Sea, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - A River Postscript, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - River Vacation, undated, rec'd 1970 Jan. (Box WP-3)
      - School Bully, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Science Fiction Water Letter to Amy Lillian, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Sea Chanty of Pegleg Plato, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Sea Text, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Season of Transfigurement, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Seasons and Houses, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Second Wind, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Seduction, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Seed Catalogue and H.P. Lovecraft, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Seraphim and The Intimation, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Seventh Part of Everything. Group of poems including Nightcap, The Wild Seventh Part, The Silver String, The Moon's Wine Red and White, Don't I Wish, Sit Down and Cry, The Seven Daughters of the King of Comets, and The Whole of It All, undated (Box WP-3)
      - Sex Manual, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-3)
      - Shazam! sez the Tiger Swallowtail Butterfly, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Signals--see Messages (Box WP-3)
      - Silent, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Silverfish, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Sitwell's Cows, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Sixth Autumn, undated, rec'd 1970 Jan. (Box WP-3)
      - Skin Flick, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Sky, undated, rec'd 1990, July (Box WP-3)
      - The Snow Drunkard and the Jolly Sleepers, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Song of the Seven, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Source, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Spider, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Spitballer, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Spring Burning, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Stars--see "Witchcraft" in Writings by Chappell Series, Fiction Subseries (Box WP-3)
      - Stoic Poet, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Story, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Subject Matter, undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-3)
      - Sunday, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Susan's Morning Dream of Gardening, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Sweetest Wind that Ever Blew: Homage to Louis, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Taste, undated Taste, undated (Box WP-3)
      - Tate's Forty Birthdays, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Tensions, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Tiger in the Field of Fire, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Third Base Coach and Extra Innings, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (2 items) (Box WP-3)
      - Three Sheets in the Wind, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Tiger in the Field of Fire, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Tiros II, ca. 1961 May (Box WP-3)
      - To the Barns, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - A Toast, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Torture: A prologue to Tolstoy's The Death of Ivan Ilych, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-3)
      - The Transformations: A Fairy Tale: Nightcap, ca. 1992 Aug. (Box WP-3)
      - A Transcendental Idealist Dreams in Springtime, 1966 Spring (Box WP-3)
      - A Transcendentalist Dreams in Springtime--see Jim Applewhite Dreams in Springtime (Box WP-3)
      - Trial by Obscenity, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Triumphal Entry of Peter Paul Reubens into Eternal Glory, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Trout Stream, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Turner, Seascape, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Ualeid, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Unfree, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Upon the Gift of a Catnip Mouse from Mary Jarrell: Christmas, 1985, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-3)
      - Utopia, undated, rec'd 1995 July (Box WP-3)
      - Victory, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Virtues, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Visitation, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - 'The Voices at Sunset,' 'Sunset,' and 'Sundown': [three poems on] Untitled Etching by Mary Ann Sloan, 1902, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-3)
      - Voyelles, undated Voyelles, undated (Box WP-3)
      - The Watchman, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-3)
      - Watchman: A prologue to the Oresteia, undated, rec'd 1987 July (Box WP-3)
      - Webern's Mountain, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Weird Tales, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - What to Buy with Purple Money, undated, rec'd Apr. 1970 (Box WP-3)
      - Where It Itches, undated Where It Itches, undated (Box WP-3)
      - Where the Rose Came From and Buy American, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Willie Rejected, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Windows, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The World Between the Eyes, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - The Worst that Could Happen, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Would you believe? ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-3)
      - Zenobia Enchained, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Zero's Other Face, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled Christmas poem for Carl Anderson, ca. 1963 Dec. (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled poem, undated, rec'd 1997 July (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled poems, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled poems, undated Untitled poems, undated (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled poems, undated, rec'd 1995 July (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled poems, undated, rec'd 1993 July (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled poems, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled poems, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WP-3)
      - Untitled poems, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Various grouped poems, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WP-3)
      - Various grouped poems, undated, rec'd 1985 Oct. (Box WP-3)
      - Various poems and workshop notes, undated (Box WP-3)
  - Essays Subseries, ca. 1960-1997 and undated
    Includes essays, longer reviews, introductions, and forewords. Arranged alphabetically by title, books first, followed by individual essays. Versions of collected essays may appear under their own title or that of the collection. Additional versions may appear in the Notebooks Subseries.
    - Plow Naked: Selected Writings on Poetry (1993) typescript, undated, 1 folder (Box WE-1)
    - Individual essays, in alphabetical order:
      - 3 Movements, undated, rec'd 1986 June (Box WE-1)
      - Candace Flynt: An Interview, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WE-1)
      - Cause of the Living Dead: Randall Jarrell at the Supermarket, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WE-1)
      - Chronicling the Culture: The Contemporary Epic Poet in his Contemporary World, undated, rec'd 1989 June (Box WE-1)
      - A Comic Novel, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WE-1)
      - Country Matters, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WE-1)
      - A Curtain Rises, 1993. See Oversize Material (Box WE-1)
      - Dr. William Blackburn, ca. 1960-1969 (Box WE-1)
      - Double Language: Three Appalachian Poets, undated, rec'd 1993 July (Box WE-1)
      - Family Matters, undated, rec'd 1993 July. See also Oversize Material (Box WE-1)
      - First Attempts, undated (Box WE-1)
      - First Attempts, undated, rec'd 1993 July (Box WE-1)